# Curriculum Vitae - Dimitri Kouvdis

#### **Frontend Developer**

Mobile: Email only please

• Email: dimitri@metaplatforms.com

• Website: dkouvdis.com

• Linkedin: uk.linkedin.com/in/dkouvdis

Github: github.com/dkouvdisBritish and EU Passport Holder

#### Note

Recruiters and Companies: Sorry no telephone interviews.

I am deaf and unable to hear over the phone. Please contact me via email - I am happy to meet in person for interviews. I require no assistance - I rely on lip-reading and speak well.

## **Profile**

I'm a Frontend developer based in London with over fourteen years of development experience, including in the commercial/FinTech industry sector. I specialise in producing high-quality interfaces for client-side applications in JavaScript, HTML5 and CSS3.

I am university educated with B-Tech in Multimedia and consistently scored over 90% in the UI/UX section of Adobe Flash projects throughout my studies. Interactive/UI developments are my specialty.

My job is not solely to write code. My aim is to deliver an exceptionally functional end product, which adheres to high standards for all platforms.

Over the years developing, I've moulded myself into a well-rounded individual who appreciates best practice and progressively keeps up with new web technologies.

## **Skills**

- JavaScript
  - o Frontend | Native [Vanilla], React, React Native, Vue, etc
  - Backend | Node, Express, Passport, etc
  - TDD (Test Driven) and BDD | Cyress, Jest, React Testing library, Jasmine, etc
  - · Build tools | Webpack, Grunt, Gulp and Node
- HTML

- Standards compliant, including WCAG 1.0 AA and WAI-ARIA
- CSS3
  - PostCSS, SASS, LESS
  - BEM and ITCSS methodology
  - Experience developing large-scale UI toolkit from scratch
  - · Love (working with, developing) functional (Atomic or Utility) css
- Devops/CI/CD
  - AWS
  - Docker
  - Vagrant
  - Jenkins
  - Gitlab
  - Kubernetes
- DB
- MongoDB
- MySQL
- Redis
- CMS
  - o Craft 3
  - ExpressionEngine
  - Statamic
- Other
  - · Git, SVN
  - Bash
  - UX (Advanced)
  - Photoshop and Sketch (Advanced)

# **Professional History**

### **Equal Experts**

December 2016 - Current

Worked for clients listed below:

Fullstack developer @ John Lewis

January 2019 - Current

Stack: Javascript (Node, React), SASS, Docker, Gitlab CI

Frontend developer @ 02

December 2018

Worked with internal CMS. Did updating outdated dependencies and refactor deperacted methods to support new libraries.

Stack: JavaScript (Express, Node, React)

• Fullstack developer @ Klarna (Tel Aviv / Berlin)

February 2018 - November 2018

Worked on login section of Klarna app in React Native - Maintained authentication services (see stack below)

Stack: JavaScript (Express, Node, React, React Native, Jest, Jasmine and etc), Docker, AWS, Jenkins, Bash

Frontend developer @ HM Revenue & Customs

January 2018

Worked closely with UX designers and produced web prototypes to improve/test the accessibility experience for users with disabilities and learning difficulties

Stack: JavaScript (Express, Node), HTML, CSS

Frontend developer @ Camelot Global

Throughout 2017

Provide support to deliver products for LoRo - FE Lead to deliver an online horse betting application to production; supported developers based in Athens (GR)/Sofia (BG) (JS - React/Redux) - Supported the Sports team develop sports betting 2.0 (JS - React/Redux) - Maintained CMS for translations (Hippo CMS) - Worked on DBG (Draw Based Games) results pages (Freemarker, HTML, SASS)

• Frontend developer @ Rightmove

December 2016

Maintained mortgage calculator micro site

Stack: JavaScript (Node), HTML, CSS

--

Freelance Frontend developer @ VICE

November 2016 - December 2016

Improved and maintained Craft CMS built site - thefifthsense.i-d.co

Stack: JavaScript (React/Redux), HTML, CSS, Freemarker

Stack: Craft CMS, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Freelance Frontend developer @ Pulse Comms

November 2016

Worked on building automated email templates to load translated contents

Stack: JavaScript (Node) and HTML

Freelance Frontend developer @ The Frameworks Spark

September 2016 - November 2016

Worked on Avios UI toolkit, built modular components for rapid development

Stack: JavaScript (Node and Handlebars), HTML, CSS

Freelance Frontend developer @ Club House

August 2016 - September 2016

Built components for Tetley. Worked on new Byron Hamburger user account section with API

Stack: JavaScript, HTML and CSS

Freelance Frontend developer @ The Frameworks Spark

April 2016 - July 2016

Worked on VW, added new features and maintenance - with Java (Grails) backend developers from Ness (Romania)

Stack: JavaScript, HTML and CSS

Freelance Frontend developer @ Future Platforms

February 2016 - March 2016

Worked on various JavaScript applications such as Premier League and Domino's

Stack: JavaScript (React & Browserify), HTML and CSS

Freelance Frontend developer @ TSL Digital

July 2015 - January 2016

Worked on various interactive projects and web banners

Stack: JavaScript, HTML and CSS

Freelance Frontend developer @ Bossa

May 2015 - July 2015

Worked for a major media company (Unable to disclose due to NDA)

Freelance Fullstack developer @ Serieseight

Jan 2015 - May 2015

Did a wide range of bespoke development solutions

Stack: ExpressionEngine, Statamic, PHP, JavaScript, LESS, Devops, SEO

Fullstack developer @ SapientRazorFish

May 2014 - October 2014

Hand-picked from BT development department to work with a Sapient team for a 6 months long revamp for Product and Services

Stack: HTML, CSS (LESS), JavaScript (Assemble.io, Handlebars, Grunt, Jquery, Angular)

Frontend developer @ BT

November 2012 - October 2014

Did many in-house and large-scale traffic projects. I was in the lead role for junior developers and did code reviews

Stack: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Handlebars

Frontend developer @ Flow Communications(Johannesburg, South Africa)

2010 - July 2012

Did a wide range of bespoke development, juggled multiple projects and responsibilities while meeting strict deadlines

Stack: ExpressionEngine, PHP, JavaScript, CSS (LESS), Devops, CI/CD

# Education

Bachelor of Technology Degree | Multimedia (2006 - 2009)